<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Priyam Alok's personal homepage</title><link>https://priyamalok.me/</link><description>Recent content on Priyam Alok's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://priyamalok.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migrating to Zola: A Practical Guide to a Faster Website</title><link>https://priyamalok.me/blog/migrating-to-zola/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://priyamalok.me/blog/migrating-to-zola/</guid><description>For the longest time, my personal website was a handful of handcrafted HTML files. It was the epitome of simplicity, and for a while, it worked perfectly. But as I added more blog posts to the &amp;ldquo;Musings&amp;rdquo; section, a familiar friction emerged: every new post meant duplicating an entire HTML file, carefully replacing the content, and hoping I didn&amp;rsquo;t break a link. This manual process was not just tedious; it was fragile.</description></item><item><title>A Pragmatic Guide to GLM and GBM for Actuaries</title><link>https://priyamalok.me/blog/a-pragmatic-guide-to-glm-and-gbm-for-actuaries/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://priyamalok.me/blog/a-pragmatic-guide-to-glm-and-gbm-for-actuaries/</guid><description>After observing the persistent debate surrounding GLM vs. GBM in insurance pricing and reserving, I decided to synthesize the core arguments and technical details into this comprehensive analysis. The goal is to move beyond a surface-level comparison and provide a valuable resource for practitioners, detailing the mathematical underpinnings, practical applications, and strategic considerations of each model.
Foundational Mathematics: A Side-by-Side Look Understanding these models begins with their mathematical architecture. One is a framework of elegant, structured assumptions; the other is a powerful, iterative algorithm.</description></item><item><title>CS1 mindmap</title><link>https://priyamalok.me/project/cs1-intractive-mindmap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://priyamalok.me/project/cs1-intractive-mindmap/</guid><description>For quick summary</description></item><item><title>CS2 mindmap</title><link>https://priyamalok.me/project/cs2-mindmap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://priyamalok.me/project/cs2-mindmap/</guid><description>For quick summary</description></item><item><title>Beyond the Framework</title><link>https://priyamalok.me/blog/beyond-the-framework-key-takeways-from-founders/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://priyamalok.me/blog/beyond-the-framework-key-takeways-from-founders/</guid><description>Key takeaways from a meeting with the PredicTri founders, on how transparency and data-driven explainability are shaping the future of actuarial work.</description></item><item><title>City of the sun :)</title><link>https://priyamalok.me/blog/city-of-the-sun/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://priyamalok.me/blog/city-of-the-sun/</guid><description>Procrastination and missed opportunities, desire for a more fulfilling life, passage of time and the realization of missed moments.</description></item></channel></rss>